SR. FREELANCE DESIGNER/PRODUCT DEVELOPMENT MANAGER

Summary

Product Development Manager/Sr. Designer of Apparel, Packaging, and Graphics. Responsible for delivering the fashion needs on a wide range of products. Ability to collaborate with the Product Development team, to execute production. Create trend/theme boards, color palettes and hand/computer sketch. Strong understanding of production as well as cost structure and technical packages. Ability to provide clear, accurate, and complete specifications for each style. Area of Expertise: Strong fabric knowledge of Cut n Sew, Woven's, & Sweaters; \hat{A} \hat{A} \hat{A}

Skills

Adobe Creative Suites-Illustrator, Photoshop, Indesign-CC, Microsoft Office- Excel, Word, Power Point, Lotus Notes, Outlook. CAD- Ned Graphics-Easy Weave, Easy Knit, Coloring and Repeat. Working knowledge of U4ia and Kaledo. PDM/PLM.

Experience

Sr. Freelance Designer/Product Development Manager 07/2012 to Current MICHELLE DESIGNS City, STATE

- Worked cross functionally while building and maintaining relationships with product development departments.
- Execute all product details including construction, detail, color, form, style, fit, graphic application, trim, etc.
- Worked directly with clients through out all stages of development to production.
- Worked with clients in selling and designing the interior of their homes at BALLARD DESIGNS/POTTERY BARN KIDS.
- Developed packaging for multiple apparel /footwear companies with TJX/AVERY DENNISON.
- Designed graphic design -t-shirts/pet wear with B POSITIVE PROJECT/PETRAGEOUS DESIGNS.
- Designed Children's apparel including sleepwear, sweater sets, rompers, dresses for BABY TOGS/BABY FAIR/ZUTANO.

Sr. Apparel Designer/Product Manager 10/2002 to 06/2012

TJX CORPORATION City, STATE

- Managed and developed product development process.
- Designed artwork and graphics for specific classifications in apparel focusing on Men's, Ladies, and Children's apparel. Â
- Worked with product teams to build and design garments that fit into a costing structure while providing new and exciting assortments.
- Cross functional leader led all teams including merchants, overseas offices, management, and product development to drive accountability and enroll the team in the commitment to meet the business objectives.
- Use relevant and appropriate resources to accurately determine, anticipate and validate current and future trends, competition, retail landscape and business drivers.
- Grew Children's Sweater business from \$100,000 business to a \$10,000.000.00 business in 10 years.
- Designed 600 unique styles in a 4 month period of time.
- Saved 30K on print development by utilizing artwork and prints from all departments.
- Monitored production flow in accordance to the company calendar.
- Reviewed WIP (work in progress) reports to ensure on time delivery.
- Provided accurate sketches including detailed close-ups for technical designs.
- Approved Submits including lab dips, knit downs, strike offs, label/packaging, and fit for production.
- Trained and mentored team of 3 Designers and 20 Freelance Contractors.

Senior Designer/Product Manager 09/1999 to 10/2002

May Merchandising Corporation City, STATE

- Merchandised and designed the product line for children's and junior's cut -n- sew, and woven fabrications.
- Supervised the sourcing process to achieve the best possible cost throughout the creation process.
- Managed sourcing and ordering of fabric yardage, and trim details for specific classifications each season.
- Created and utilized PDM to design sketches and specification pages.
- Attended all fittings for prototype meetings and production samples.
- Responsible for merchandising the Apparel product per delivery.
- Partnered with team throughout the development cycle from initial tech pack, print and fabrications to end product.
- Responsible for completing all technical line drawings, keeping visual needs up to date, building detailed tech packs.
- Present effectively and confidently to all levels of the organization Prepares global price proposals using established tools and guidelines.
- Consulted with Buyers and MMC when competitive situations arise.
- Traveled to overseas offices in Asia 2-4 times a year to ensure correct fabrication, development, and execution of production was accurate.
- Strong organizational, time management, communication and presentation skills.
- Managed 2 designers, created and mentored the designer's pathway for growth to be promoted.

Home Textiles Account Manager AMC/Target Corporation City, STATE

- Managed development process from design to implementation-home d\(\tilde{A}\)\(\tilde{\text{Cor}}\), candles, seasonal products, domestics, and home textiles.
- Worked with the overseas factories to sample, negotiate price and package the line items for sale.
- Worked with buyers in development and offshore sourcing for seasonal programs.
- Presented and merchandised plan-o-gram with Buyer for seasonal programs and end caps.
- Worked with the designers on creating bedding, and window treatments to create a mix and match line.

- Responsible for executing key strategies for all projects, while creating mood boards to aid buyers.
- Managed a team of 4 Assistants.

Education and Training

Bachelor of Science : Textile Design 1992 Syracuse University City , State

Skille

Product/Brand Development Trend/ColorÂ Sourcing/Negotiation Print Repeat/Textile Design Technical Fit Knitwear Expert